We're not clear yet.
There are still 30 pallets
of cannon shells in C bunker.
Forget the munitions,
there's no time.
Just get everyone
on the transports.
Oh, no.
We've caught them in the
middle of their evacuation.
I have my orders from
Supreme Leader Snoke himself.
This is where we snuff out
the Resistance once and for all.
Tell Captain Canady
to prime his dreadnought.
Incinerate their base, destroy their
transports and obliterate their fleet.
General, Resistance ship approaching.
Guns and shields in attack mode.
A single light fighter.
Happy beeps here, buddy, come on.
We've pulled crazier stunts than this.
Just for the record,
Commander Dameron,
I'm with the droid on this one.
Thank you for your support, General.
Happy beeps.
Attention.
This is Commander Poe Dameron
of the Republic fleet,
I have an urgent
communiqué for General Hugs.
Patch him through.
This is General Hux
of the First Order.
The Republic is no more.
Your fleet are Rebel scum
and war criminals.
Tell your precious princess
there will be no terms,
there will be no surrender.
Hi, I'm holding for General Hugs.
This is Hux.
You and your friends are doomed.
We will wipe your filth
from the galaxy.
Okay. I'll hold.
Hello?
Hello? Yup.
I'm still here.
Can he hear me?
- Hugs?
- He can.
With an "H." Skinny guy.
Kinda pasty.
I can hear you.
Can you hear me?
Look, I can't hold forever.
If you reach him,
tell him Leia has
an urgent message for him...
I believe he's tooling with you, sir.
...about his mother.
Open fire!
BB-8, punch it!
He's going for the dreadnought.
Ha!
He's insane.
Woo-hoo! That's got a kick.
All right, taking out the cannons now.
Tallie, start your approach.
Copy that.
Captain Canady,
why aren't you blasting that puny ship?
That puny ship is too small
and at too close range.
We need to scramble our fighters
five bloody minutes ago.
He'll never penetrate our armor.
He's not trying to penetrate our armor.
He's clearing out our surface cannons.
One cannon left.
And here comes the parade.
Yeah! Yeah, I see him!
No, no, no.
Damn it!
BB-8, my weapons systems are down.
We gotta take out that last cannon
or our bombers are toast.
Work your magic, buddy.
Are the auto-cannons primed?
Primed and ready, sir.
What are we waiting for?
Fire on the base!
Punch it!
The last transport is in the air.
The evacuation is complete.
You did it, Poe.
Now get your squad back here
so we can get out of this place.
No, General...
We can do this.
We have the chance
to take out a dreadnought.
These things are fleet killers.
We can't let it get away.
Disengage now...
Commander.
That is an or...
Wipe that nervous expression
off your face, Threepio.
Oh. Well,
I will certainly try, General.
Nervous?
Let's go, BB-8.
It's now or never!
Yes!
All clear! Bring the bombs.
Captain,
Resistance bombers approaching.
Of course they are.
Bombers, keep that tight formation.
Fighters, protect the bombers.
It's not every day we
get a shot at a dreadnought,
so let's make this count.
Copy that, Blue Leader.
You get us there,
we'll give it to them.
- Copy. We're on it.
- Fighters incoming.
Gunners, look alive.
Snubfighters at two-ten!
- They're coming in!
- Form up!
They're everywhere!
Here they come.
Incoming fighters.
Form up.
Vector in at attack speed.
- Pull up!
- Flank right.
Mayday! Mayday!
Mayday! We're going down!
Recharge the auto-cannons.
Target their cruiser.
I see it. Tallie,
they've targeted the fleet
and begun the priming sequence.
Copy that.
We're almost there.
Bombardiers, begin your drop sequence.
I've got a visual on the target.
We're approaching the sweet spot.
Bombs are armed.
- Auto-cannons aimed.
- Forty seconds to full charge.
Destroy that last bomber!
Paige, come in.
We're over the target.
Why aren't your bay doors open?
You're the only bomber left.
It's all down to you!
- Nix!
- Paige!
Drop the payload now!
Look out!
No!
Bombs away!
Direct hit! Dreadnought down!
General, Supreme Leader Snoke
is making contact from his ship.
Excellent.
I'll take it in my chambers.
General Hux.
Ah, good. Supreme Lea...
My disappointment
in your performance cannot be overstated.
They can't get away, Supreme Leader.
We have them tied on the end of a string.
Rey!
Well done, pal.
"Finn naked leaking bag"?
What? Did you fry a chip?
Finn! Finn, buddy.
It's so good to see you.
What? Let's...
We need to get you dressed.
Come on.
You must have a thousand questions.
Where's Rey?
Master Skywalker?
I'm from the Resistance.
Your sister Leia sent me.
We need your help.
Hello?
Go away.
Chewie, what are you doing here?
He said you're coming back with us.
How did you find me?
Long story.
We'll tell you on the Falcon.
Falcon?
Wait.
Where's Han?
Tied on a string indeed,
General Hux. Well done.
The Resistance will soon
be in our grasp.
Thank you, Supreme Leader.
You wonder why I keep a rabid cur
in such a place of power?
A cur's weakness,
properly manipulated,
can be a sharp tool.
How's your wound?
It's nothing.
Hmm.
The mighty Kylo Ren.
When I found you,
I saw what all masters live to see.
Raw, untamed power.
And beyond that, something truly special.
The potential of your bloodline.
A new Vader.
Now I fear
I was mistaken.
I've given everything I have to you.
To the dark side.
Take that ridiculous thing off.
Yes, there it is.
You have too much
of your father's heart in you,
young Solo.
I killed Han Solo.
When the moment came,
I didn't hesitate.
And look at you,
the deed split your spirit to the bone.
You were unbalanced,
bested by a girl
who had never held a lightsaber!
You failed!
Skywalker lives.
The seed of the Jedi Order lives.
And as long as it does,
hope lives in the galaxy.
I thought you would be the one
to snuff it out.
Alas, you're no Vader.
You're just a child
in a mask.
Prepare my ship.
There's no light
left in Kylo Ren.
He's only getting stronger.
The First Order will control
all the major systems within weeks.
We need your help.
We need the Jedi Order back.
We need Luke Skywalker.
You don't need Luke Skywalker.
Did you hear a word I just said?
You think what?
I'm gonna walk out with a laser sword
and face down the whole First Order?
What did you think
was going to happen here?
You think that I came
to the most unfindable place
in the galaxy for no reason at all?
Go away.
I'm not leaving without you!
Careful!
You're wasting your time.
Who are you?
I know this place.
Built a thousand generations ago
to keep these.
The original Jedi texts.
Just like me,
they're the last of the Jedi religion.
You've seen this place.
You've seen this island.
Only in dreams.
Who are you?
The Resistance sent me.
They sent you?
What's special about you?
- Where are you from?
- Nowhere.
- No one's from nowhere.
- Jakku.
All right,
that is pretty much nowhere.
Why are you here, Rey,
from nowhere?
The Resistance sent me.
We need your help.
The First Order's become unstoppable.
Why are you here?
Something inside me has always been there.
But now it's awake.
And I'm afraid.
I don't know what it is
or what to do with it.
And I need help.
You need a teacher.
I can't teach you.
Why not?
I've seen your daily routine.
You're not busy.
I will never train
another generation of Jedi.
I came to this island to die.
It's time for the Jedi to end.
Why?
Leia sent me here with hope.
If she was wrong,
she deserves to know why.
We all do.
- You're demoted.
- What? Wait!
- We took down a dreadnought.
- At what cost?
You start an attack,
you follow it through.
Poe, get your head out of your cockpit.
There are things that you cannot solve
by jumping in an X-wing
and blowing something up!
I need you to learn that.
There were heroes on that mission.
Dead heroes.
No leaders.
We're really nowhere.
How's Rey gonna find us now?
A cloaked binary beacon.
To light her way home.
All right, so until she gets back,
what's the plan?
We need to find a new base.
One with enough power
to get a distress signal
to our allies scattered in the Outer Rim.
Proximity alert!
They found us.
That's impossible.
That's Snoke's ship.
You gotta be kidding me.
- Can we jump to lightspeed?
- We have enough
fuel resources for just one jump.
Well, then, do it.
We gotta get out of here.
Wait.
They've tracked us through lightspeed.
That's impossible.
Yes.
And they've done it.
So if we jump through lightspeed,
they'll just find us again
and we'll be out of fuel.
They've got us.
Not yet, they don't.
Permission to jump in an X-wing
and blow something up?
Permission granted.
Admiral, swing us around!
Full astern.
Rotate shields!
To your stations! Move, move, move!
Follow my lead.
Green Squadron to launch position.
Clear all launch traffic.
Don't wait for me!
Jump in and fire her up!
Technicians,
lock down supplies for launch conditions.
Move! Move!
Poe, are you all right?
We need to get out of range
of those Star Destroyers.
We need to what?
Full engines ahead.
Get out of range of the Star Destroyers
and the fighters will fall back.
All craft, full engines!
Concentrate rear shields.
Ren, the Resistance
have pulled out of range.
We can't cover you at this distance.
Return to the fleet.
What is the point of all this
if we can't blow up three tiny cruisers?
Well, they're faster and lighter, sir.
They can't lose us,
but they can keep at a range
where our cannons are ineffective
against their shields.
Well, keep up the barrage.
Let's at least remind them
that we're still here.
Very good, sir.
They won't last long
burning fuel like this.
It's just a matter of time.
Move! Out of the way, everybody!
Give room!
Life signs are weak,
but she's fighting.
Artoo?
Artoo!
Yes.
Yeah, I know.
Hey, sacred island, watch the language.
Old friend.
I wish I could make you understand.
But I'm not coming back.
Nothing can make me
change my mind.
Years ago, you served my father
in the Clone Wars.
Now he begs you to help him
in his struggle against the Empire.
I regret that I am unable to present
my father's request to you in person...
That was a cheap move.
...but my ship
has fallen under attack,
and I'm afraid my mission
to bring you to Alderaan has failed.
This is our most desperate hour.
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
You're my only hope.
Tomorrow at dawn.
Three lessons.
I will teach you the ways of the Jedi
and why they need to end.
General Organa,
Leia,
is unconscious but recovering.
That's the only good news I have.
Admiral Ackbar,
all our leadership, they're gone.
Leia was the sole survivor
on the bridge.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear!
If she were here, she'd say
save your sorrow for after the fight.
To that end,
the chain of command is clear
as to who should take her place.
Vice Admiral Holdo
of the cruiser Ninka.
Thank you, Commander.
Four hundred of us
on three ships.
We're the very last
of the Resistance.
But we're not alone.
In every corner of the galaxy,
the downtrodden and oppressed
know our symbol,
and they put their hope in it.
We are the spark
that will light the fire that
will restore the Republic.
That spark,
this Resistance, must survive.
That is our mission.
Now, to your stations.
And may the Force be with us.
That's Admiral Holdo?
Battle of Chyron Belt Admiral Holdo?
Not what I expected.
Vice Admiral?
Commander Dameron.
With our current fuel consumption,
there's a very limited amount of time
that we can stay out of range
of those Star Destroyers.
Very kind of you
to make me aware.
Let's get me those fuel projections.
And we need to shake 'em
before we can find a new base, so,
what's our plan?
Our plan, captain?
Not commander, right?
Wasn't it Leia's last official act
to demote you
for your dreadnought plan
where we lost our entire bombing fleet?
"Captain." "Commander."
You can call me whatever you like.
I just wanna know what's going on.
Of course you do.
I understand.
I've dealt with plenty
of trigger-happy flyboys like you.
You're impulsive.
Dangerous.
And the last thing
we need right now.
So stick to your post
and follow my orders.
Turbolink banks seven and eight
are offline due to maintenance.
What are you doing here?
Hey. Hi.
Uh, I was...
You know, I was just...
You're Finn!
The Finn!
- The Finn?
- Sorry.
I work behind pipes all day.
Doing talking with Resistance heroes
is not my forte.
Doing...
Doing talking.
I'm Rose.
Breathe.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Look, I'm not a Resistance hero,
but it was nice talking to you, Rose.
May the Force be with you.
Wow. You, too.
Okay. But you are a hero.
You left the First Order,
what you did on the Starkiller Base...
When we heard about it,
my sister Paige said,
"Rose, that's a real hero."
"Know right from wrong
"and don't run away
when it gets hard," she said.
You know...
Just this morning, I've had to stun
three people trying to
jump ship in this escape pod.
- What?
- They were running away.
That's disgraceful.
I know.
Anyway, uh...
Gotta get back to
what I was doing, so...
What were you doing?
Uh, just...
- Doing some checks.
- Checking the escape pods.
- No, it's routine checks.
- By boarding one
with a packed bag.
Okay.
Listen, I'm...
I can't move.
- I know.
- What happened?
I'm taking you to the brig
and turning you in for desertion.
I was not deserting.
- I told you that...
- My sister just died
protecting the fleet.
And you were running away.
I'm sorry.
But this fleet is doomed,
and if my friend comes back to it,
she's doomed, too.
I've gotta get this...
I gotta get this beacon
far away from here.
Then she'll find me and be safe.
You're a selfish traitor.
Look, we can't outrun
the First Order fleet.
We can jump to lightspeed!
Well, they can track us
through lightspeed.
They can track us through lightspeed?
Yeah.
They'd just show up
thirty seconds later
and we'd have
blown a ton of fuel,
which, by the way,
we're dangerously short on.
They can track us through lightspeed.
Yes. And they could...
I can't feel my teeth.
What did you shoot me with?
Active tracking.
What now?
Hyperspace tracking is new tech
but the principle must be
the same as any active tracker.
- They're only tracking us...
- Only tracking us...
...from the lead ship.
But we can't get to the tracker.
It's an A-class process,
they'll control it from the main bridge.
Well, I mean, yes,
but every A-class process...
...has a dedicated power breaker.
But... Wait, but who knows
where the breaker room
is on a Star Destroyer?
I'm the guy that used to mop it.
If I can get us there,
I can shut their tracker down.
Just give it to me
one more time, simpler.
So, the First Order's only tracking us
from one Destroyer, the lead one.
So we blow that one up?
I like where your head's at, but no.
They'd only start tracking us
from another Destroyer.
But if we can...
If we sneak on board the lead Destroyer
and disable the tracker
without them realizing, then we can...
They won't realize it's off
for one system cycle.
- About six minutes.
- Sneak on board.
Disable the tracker.
Our fleet escapes before they realize.
Hmm.
How'd you two meet?
Just luck.
Yeah?
Good luck?
Not sure yet.
Poe, we gotta do this.
It'll save the fleet and it'll save Rey.
If I must be
the sole voice of reason,
Admiral Holdo will never
agree to this plan.
Yeah, you're right, Threepio.
It's a "need-to-know" plan,
and she doesn't.
- That wasn't exactly my...
- All right,
you guys shut down that tracker.
I'll be here to jump us to lightspeed.
The question is,
how do we sneak the two of you
onto Snoke's Destroyer?
We steal clearance codes.
No, they're bio-hexacrypt
and rescrambled every hour.
We can't get through their
security shields undetected.
Nobody can.
Could I do it?
Of course I could do it.
But I can't do it.
I'm a little tied down right now.
Oh!
Maz? What is happening?
Union dispute.
You do not want to hear about it.
But, lucky for you,
there's exactly one guy I trust
who can crack that kind of security!
He's a master codebreaker,
an ace pilot,
a poet with a blaster.
Oh, my.
It sounds like this codebreaker fellow
can do everything.
Oh, yes, he can.
You'll find him with a red
plom bloom on his lapel
rolling at a high stakes table
in the casino on Canto Bight.
Canto Bight? No, no.
That's... Maz...
Is there any way that we can
take care of this ourselves?
Sorry, kiddo.
This is rarefied cracking.
You wanna get on that Destroyer,
I only know one option.
Find the Master Codebreaker.
You'll bring Luke Skywalker to me.
You're not doing this.
The effort would kill you.
Can you see my surroundings?
You're gonna pay for what you did!
I can't see yours.
Just you.
So, no.
This is something else.
Luke.
What's that about?
I was cleaning my blaster.
It went off.
Let's get started.
Who were those things?
Caretakers.
Island natives.
They've kept up the Jedi structures
since they were built.
I don't think they like me.
Can't imagine why.
Master Skywalker,
we need you to bring the Jedi back
because Kylo Ren is strong
with the dark side of the Force.
Without the Jedi, we won't
stand a chance against him.
What do you know
about the Force?
It's a power that Jedi have
that lets them control people
and make things float.
Impressive.
Every word in that sentence was wrong.
Lesson one, sit here, legs crossed.
The Force is not a power you have.
It's not about lifting rocks.
It's the energy between all things,
a tension, a balance,
that binds the universe together.
Okay.
But what is it?
Close your eyes.
Breathe.
Now,
reach out.
I feel something.
- You feel it?
- Yes, I feel it.
- That's the Force.
- Really?
Wow, it must be
really strong with you.
I've never felt any...
Ow!
You meant reach out like...
I'll try again.
Breathe.
Just breathe.
Reach out with your feelings.
What do you see?
The island.
Life.
Death and decay,
that feeds new life.
Warmth.
Cold.
Peace.
Violence.
And between it all?
Balance.
An energy.
A Force.
And inside you?
Inside me
that same Force.
And this is the lesson.
That Force does not
belong to the Jedi.
To say that if the Jedi die,
the light dies, is vanity.
Can you feel that?
There's something else
beneath the island.
A place.
A dark place.
Balance.
Powerful light, powerful darkness.
It's cold.
It's calling me.
Resist it, Rey.
Rey?
Rey!
You went straight to the dark.
That place was trying
to show me something.
It offered something you needed.
And you didn't even try
to stop yourself.
But I didn't see you.
Nothing from you.
You've closed yourself off
from the Force.
Of course you have.
I've seen this raw strength
only once before,
in Ben Solo.
It didn't scare me enough then.
It does now.
What was that?
Nothing, admiral.
Passing debris.
The fleet's only got
18 hours of fuel left.
We gotta hurry.
Still can't reach the Resistance?
Keep at it.
If you get through, check their status.
And ask about Finn.
Why is the Force connecting us?
You and I.
Murderous snake.
You're too late.
You lost. I found Skywalker.
Did he tell you what happened?
The night I destroyed his temple,
did he tell you why?
I know everything
I need to know about you.
You do?
Ah, you do.
You have that look in your eyes.
From the forest.
When you called me a monster.
You are a monster.
Yes, I am.
Okay.
We get in, we find this codebreaker,
we get out.
You know this town? Canto Bight?
From stories.
It's a terrible place filled with
the worst people in the galaxy.
Great.
I told those two, I said,
"This is a public beach.
You can't park that shuttle here."
But they just lit off toward the casino.
Place your bets.
All bets on the table
right now, right now!
Place your bets here.
Aw, yes!
This place is great!
Okay.
Maz said this Master Codebreaker
would have a red plom bloom on his lapel.
Let's find him and get out of here.
Well played.
The house wins.
Where are
your manners, more like?
Come on!
We've covered this whole casino.
Zero red plom blooms.
Where is this guy?
Were those what I think they were?
- What are those things?
- Fathiers.
I've never seen a real one.
Look, this whole place is beautiful.
I mean, come on.
Why do you hate it so much?
Look closer.
My sister and I grew up
in a poor mining system.
The First Order stripped our ore
to finance their military
then shelled us
to test their weapons.
They took everything we had.
And who do you think
these people are?
There's only one business in the galaxy
that'll get you this rich.
War.
Selling weapons to the First Order.
I wish I could put my fist through this
whole lousy, beautiful town.
Red plom bloom!
The Master Codebreaker!
Yep, those are the shuttle parkers.
All right.
You two are under arrest
for parking violation 27B/6.
You have the right to remain...
- What was that?
- No, no, no. Not now, Lovey.
I'm on a roll.
Lesson two.
Now that they're extinct,
the Jedi are romanticized, deified.
But if you strip away the myth
and look at their deeds,
the legacy of the Jedi is failure.
Hypocrisy, hubris.
That's not true.
At the height of their powers,
they allowed Darth Sidious to rise
create the Empire, and wipe them out.
It was a Jedi Master
who was responsible
for the training
and creation of Darth Vader.
And a Jedi who saved him.
Yes, the most hated man in the galaxy.
But you saw there was conflict inside him.
You believed that he wasn't gone.
That he could be turned.
And I became a legend.
For many years, there was balance
and then I saw
Ben.
My nephew
with that mighty Skywalker blood.
And in my hubris,
I thought I could train him,
I could pass on my strengths.
Han was Han about it, but...
Leia
trusted me with her son.
I took him,
and a dozen students,
and began a training temple.
By the time I realized
I was no match for
the darkness rising in him,
it was too late.
What happened?
I went to confront him.
And he turned on me.
Ben, no!
He must have thought
I was dead.
When I came to,
the temple was burning.
He had vanished
with a handful of my students.
And slaughtered the rest.
Leia blamed Snoke,
but it was me.
I failed.
Because I was Luke Skywalker.
Jedi Master.
A legend.
The galaxy may need a legend.
I need someone to show me
my place in all this.
And you didn't fail Kylo.
Kylo failed you.
I won't.
The main cruiser's
still keeping beyond range.
But their medical frigate is out of fuel
and its shields are down.
The beginning of their end.
Destroy it.
The last of our crew has been evacuated
and heading your way.
It's been an honor, admiral.
Godspeed, Rebels!
Admiral,
fuel reserves at six hours.
Maintain our current course.
Steady on.
Finn,
Rose, where are you guys?
Deal me in.
Thanks.
Finn, the fleet
is running on fumes.
Without a codebreaker
to break us onto Snoke's Star Destroyer...
- What do we do?
- I don't know.
Unless you got a thief in your pocket,
our plan is shot.
Um, I can do it.
What?
S-S-Sorry, I just
couldn't help but overhear all the stuff
that you were saying really loudly
while I was trying to sleep.
Codebreaker?
Thief?
I can do it.
We're not talking about
picking pockets, okay?
Yeah.
D-D-Don't let the wrapper
fool you, friend.
Me and the First Order
codeage go way back.
And,
if the price is right,
I could break you into
old man S-S-Snoke's boudoir.
- No.
- We're... We got it covered.
Ha-tuk-ga.
- Did he just...
- Yeah.
We gotta get out of here!
This way!
Why you little...
D-D-Did you do this?
Hey, hands up!
- Hands up!
- Yeah, man.
What's your story, roundie?
They went this way!
- Lock down all the exits.
- Wait.
That smelled great.
Those cops will be here
any minute. What now?
Whoa! Ooh!
No, wait.
Please, don't!
We're with the Resistance.
Roger that.
Checking the stables now.
This way.
They must have
come through here.
Hyah!
Go, go, go! Whoo!
Stop enjoying this!
We've got them.
They're not going anywhere.
Ahhh!
Huh?
Move, move, move!
Get out of the way!
Our ship's on the beach straight ahead!
We need cover!
Too much cover!
There it is!
- No!
- Come on!
Let the herd go.
Stick with the perps.
Where'd they go?
I think we lost him!
Now we get down to the beach
and circle back around...
Cliff!
We're trapped.
It was worth it, though.
To tear up that town,
make 'em hurt.
Go.
Now it's worth it.
There they are.
BB-8! Wait, are you flying that thing?
Ah.
N-N-Need a lift?
Luke.
Leia.
I'd rather not do this now.
Yeah, me, too.
Why did you hate your father?
Do you have something,
a cowl or something you could put on?
Why did you hate your father?
Give me an honest answer.
You had a father who loved you,
he gave a damn about you.
- I didn't hate him.
- Then why?
Why what?
Why what? Say it.
Why did you...
Why did you kill him?
I don't understand.
No?
Your parents threw you away
like garbage.
- They didn't!
- They did.
But you can't stop needing them.
It's your greatest weakness.
Looking for them everywhere,
in Han Solo,
now in Skywalker.
Did he tell you what happened
that night?
Yes.
No.
He had sensed my power,
as he senses yours.
And he feared it.
Liar.
Let the past die.
Kill it if you have to.
That's the only way to become
what you were meant to be.
No! No!
Rey?
I should have felt
trapped or panicked.
But I didn't.
This didn't go on forever,
I knew it was leading somewhere.
And that, at the end,
it would show me what I came to see.
Rey.
Let me see them.
My parents,
please.
I thought I'd find answers here.
I was wrong.
I'd never felt so alone.
You're not alone.
Neither are you.
Rey?
It isn't too late.
Stop!
Is it true?
Did you try to murder him?
Leave this island now!
Stop.
Stop!
Did you do it?
Did you create Kylo Ren?
Tell me the truth.
I saw darkness.
I'd sensed it building in him.
I'd seen it in moments
during his training.
But then I looked inside,
and it was beyond
what I ever imagined.
Snoke had already turned his heart.
He would bring destruction,
and pain, and death,
and the end of everything I love
because of what he will become.
And for the briefest moment
of pure instinct,
I thought I could stop it.
It passed like a fleeting shadow.
And I was left with shame,
and with consequence.
And the last thing I saw
were the eyes of a frightened boy
whose master had failed him.
Ben, no!
You failed him by thinking
his choice was made.
It wasn't.
There's still conflict in him.
If he were turned from the dark side,
that could shift the tide.
This could be how we win.
This is not going to go
the way you think.
It is.
Just now when we touched hands,
I saw his future.
As solid as I'm seeing you.
If I go to him, Ben Solo will turn.
Rey,
don't do this.
Then he's our last hope.
Master Yoda.
Young Skywalker.
I'm ending all of this.
The tree, the text, the Jedi.
I'm gonna burn it down.
Hmm.
Ah, Skywalker.
Missed you, have I.
So it is time
for the Jedi Order to end.
Time it is.
Hmm.
For you to look past
a pile of old books, hmm?
The sacred Jedi texts.
Oh. Read them, have you?
- Well, I...
- Page-turners
they were not.
Yes, yes, yes.
Wisdom they held,
but that library contained
nothing that the girl Rey
does not already possess.
Skywalker,
still looking to the horizon.
Never here, now, hmm?
The need in front of your nose.
Hmm?
I was weak.
Unwise.
Lost Ben Solo, you did.
Lose Rey, we must not.
I can't be what she needs me to be.
Heeded my words not, did you?
Pass on what you have learned.
Strength, mastery.
But weakness,
folly, failure also.
Yes, failure most of all.
The greatest teacher, failure is.
Luke,
we are what they grow beyond.
That is the true burden of all masters.
Four parsecs to go.
This thing really cooks.
I just hope we're in time.
You can actually do this, right?
Yeah, about that...
Guys, I can do it.
But there exists a pre- "do it"
conversation about price.
Once we're done, the Resistance
will give you whatever you want.
What you got deposit-wise?
Are you kidding me?
Look at us.
Is that Haysian smelt?
That's something.
No, we gave you our word.
You're gonna get paid.
That should be enough.
Guys, I wanna keep helping.
But no something, n-n-no doing.
Okay, listen here, you've got...
Do it.
Now I can help.
Give it back.
What?
Give it back!
You have no idea how much
that medallion means to her.
What are you... Why are you
ransacking your own ship?
It's not your ship.
He says I stole it.
- Yeah, I got that.
- We stole it.
At least you're stealing
from the bad guys
and helping the good.
Good guys, bad guys,
made-up words.
Let's see who formerly owned
this gorgeous hunk-uh.
Ah, this guy was an arms dealer.
Made his bank selling weapons
to the bad guys.
Oh...
And the good.
Finn, let me learn you something big.
It's all a machine, partner.
Live free, don't join.
That was the last of their support ships.
It's just their main cruiser now.
And their fuel reserve?
By our calculation,
critical.
She in there?
The admiral's banned you
from the bridge.
- Let's not have a scene.
- No, let's.
- Holdo?
- You're not allowed in here.
- Flyboy.
- Cut it, lady.
We had a fleet,
now we're down to one ship,
and you've told us nothing!
Tell us that we have a plan!
That there's hope!
When I served under Leia,
she would say,
hope is like the sun.
If you only believe in it
when you can see it...
You'll never make it
through the night.
Yes.
Are you fueling up the transports?
You are.
All of them?
We're abandoning ship? Is that...
That's what you got?
That's what you brought us to?
Coward!
Those transport ships
are unarmed, unshielded.
We abandon this cruiser, we're done.
We don't stand a chance.
No, you are not just a coward,
you are a traitor.
Get this man off my bridge.
Finn,
Holdo's loading the crew in the shuttle.
She's going to abandon ship.
Where are you?
Poe, we're on our way
back to the fleet.
We're so close.
Did you find the Master Codebreaker?
Well, we found a codebreaker.
We can shut the tracker down.
Just buy us a little more time.
All right. Hurry.
As soon as I launch,
you jump back out of range.
Stay there until you get my signal
for where to rendezvous.
If you see Finn before I do,
tell him...
Yeah, perfect.
Tell him that.
Cloaking our approach.
We should be off their scopes.
Then we slice a slit in their shield.
Blip bloppity bloop,
and slip right through.
So a stormtrooper
and a who now are doing what?
They are trying to save us.
This is our best chance for escape.
You have to give Finn and Rose
all the time that you can.
You have bet the survival
of the Resistance
on bad odds and put us all at risk.
There's no time now.
We have to get clear of the cruiser.
Load the transports.
Right away, admiral.
Yeah, I was afraid you'd say that.
Vice Admiral Holdo,
I am relieving you
of your command
for the survival of this ship,
its crew, and the Resistance.
I hope you understand
what you're doing.
Yeah.
I'm going to the bridge.
If they move, stun them.
...at least three cycles so far.
Yes, sir.
We are working on it.
I will do my best, sir.
Almost there.
You don't have to do this.
I feel the conflict in you.
It's tearing you apart.
Ben, when we touched hands,
I saw your future.
Just the shape of it,
but solid and clear.
You will not bow before Snoke.
You'll turn.
I'll help you.
I saw it.
I saw something, too.
Because of what I saw,
I know when the moment comes,
you'll be the one to turn.
You'll stand with me.
Rey,
I saw who your parents are.
Well done, my good
and faithful apprentice.
My faith in you is restored.
Young Rey.
Welcome.
So this is it.
The tracker's right behind this door.
Haysian smelt.
Best conductor.
And you're welcome.
Good time to figure out
how we get back to the fleet?
I know where the nearest escape pods are.
Course you do.
BB-8, tell me something good.
Poe, we're almost there.
Have the cruiser prepped for lightspeed.
Yeah, I'm on it, pal.
You just hurry.
Clear the bridge, escort the
officers down to the hangar.
Commander...
Captain Dameron,
Admiral Holdo was looking for you.
Yeah, we spoke.
Sir, I am almost afraid to ask.
Good instinct, Threepio.
Go with that.
Seal that door!
We're running out of time.
Come on, how's it going?
Almost there.
Threepio, where do you think
you're going?
It would be quite against
my programming
- to be party to a mutiny.
- Hey!
It is not correct protocol.
Oh! Neither is this!
Finn? We're ready to make the jump!
Now or never.
Now.
You're up.
- You there, hands up!
- Watch 'em, watch 'em.
- Drop your weapons, now!
- Hands up, Rebel scum.
Get down! I said, down!
FN-2187.
So good to have you back.
They didn't make it.
Leia.
Please board the transports
according to your
evacuation designation.
All transports must be cleared...
Okay,
help me push him up, guys.
That one's a troublemaker.
I like him.
Me, too.
Now, time to board your transport.
For the transports to escape,
someone needs to stay behind
and pilot the cruiser.
Too many losses.
I can't take any more.
Sure you can.
You taught me how.
May the Force be...
You go on.
I've said it enough.
May the Force be with you always.
Cloaking device activated.
We should be off their scopes.
Let's hope this works.
Come closer, child.
So much strength.
Darkness rises,
and light to meet it.
I warned my young apprentice
that as he grew stronger,
his equal in the light would rise.
Skywalker...
I assumed.
Wrongly.
Closer, I said.
You underestimate Skywalker,
and Ben Solo,
and me.
It will be your downfall.
Oh...
Have you seen something?
A weakness in my apprentice.
Is that why you came?
Young fool.
It was I who bridged your minds.
I stoked Ren's conflicted soul.
I knew he was not strong enough
to hide it from you.
And you were not wise enough
to resist the bait.
And now,
you will give me Skywalker.
Then I will kill you
with the cruelest stroke.
No.
Yes.
Give me
everything.
No! No!
No!
No. No.
No, no, no!
Poe.
What is that?
The mineral planet, Crait.
An uncharted hideout from
the days of the Rebellion.
- That's a Rebel base?
- Abandoned,
but heavily armored
with enough power
to get a distress signal to our allies
scattered in the Outer Rim.
Holdo knew the First Order
was tracking our big ship.
They're not monitoring
for little transports.
So we could slip down
to the surface unnoticed
and hide till the First Order passes.
That could work.
She was more interested
in protecting the light than she was
seeming like a hero.
Godspeed,
Rebels.
Well done, Phasma.
Your ship and payment, as we agreed.
You lying snake.
We got caught,
I cut a d-d-deal.
Wait,
cut a deal with what?
Sir, we checked on the
information from the thief.
We ran a decloaking scan,
and sure enough,
30 Resistance transports
have just launched from the cruiser.
He told us the truth.
Will wonders never cease?
No.
Our weapons are ready?
Ready and aimed, sir.
Fire at will.
Wait. No, no.
No, you can't!
No!
Admiral, we're taking fire!
- Do we turn around?
- No, you're too far out.
Full speed to planetfall.
Full speed!
Well, well,
I did not expect Skywalker
to be so wise.
We will give him and the Jedi Order
the death he desires.
After the Rebels are gone,
we will go to his planet
and obliterate the entire island.
Such spunk.
Look here now.
The entire Resistance
on those transports...
Soon they will all be gone.
For you, all is lost.
Ooh. And still that
fiery spit of hope.
You have the spirit of a true Jedi!
And because of that,
you must die.
My worthy apprentice,
son of darkness,
heir apparent to Lord Vader.
Where there was conflict,
I now sense resolve.
Where there was weakness, strength.
Complete your training,
and fulfill your destiny.
I know what I have to do.
Ben.
You think you can turn him?
Pathetic child.
I cannot be betrayed,
I cannot be beaten.
I see his mind,
I see his every intent.
Yes.
I see him turning
the lightsaber to strike true.
And now,
foolish child,
he ignites it,
and kills his true enemy!
Come on, give it full thrusters.
Full speed!
I am, sir.
You murdering bastard!
T-T-Take it easy, Big F.
They blow you up today,
you blow them up tomorrow.
It's just business.
You're wrong.
Maybe.
Ben!
The fleet.
Order them to stop firing.
There's still time to save the fleet.
Ben?
It's time to let old things die.
Snoke,
Skywalker.
The Sith,
the Jedi, the Rebels...
Let it all die.
Rey.
I want you to join me.
We can rule together
and bring a new order to the galaxy.
Don't do this, Ben.
Please don't go this way.
No, no. You're still
holding on! Let go!
Do you wanna know the truth
about your parents?
Or have you always known?
And you've just hidden it away.
You know the truth.
Say it.
They were nobody.
They were filthy junk traders
who sold you off for drinking money.
They're dead in a paupers'
grave in the Jakku desert.
You have no place in this story.
You come from nothing.
You're nothing.
But not to me.
Join me.
Please.
Sir,
the Resistance cruiser's
preparing to jump to lightspeed.
It's empty.
They're just trying
to pull our attention away.
Pathetic.
Keep your fire on the transports.
Execution by blaster
is too good for them.
Let's make this hurt.
Finn.
On my command.
She's running away.
No, she isn't.
- No!
- Fire on that cruiser!
Execute.
Finn!
There's a shuttle back that way!
We gotta go!
Traitor!
What?
Finn!
You are a bug in the system.
Let's go, chrome dome.
Come on!
No!
Hey.
You were always scum.
Rebel scum.
Hey! Need a lift?
What happened?
The girl murdered Snoke.
She took Snoke's escape craft.
We know where she's going.
Get all our forces down
to that Resistance base.
Let's finish this.
Finish this?
Who do you think you're talking to?
You presume to command my army?
Our Supreme Leader is dead!
We have no ruler!
The Supreme Leader is dead.
Long live the Supreme Leader.
They're coming, shut the door.
Incoming!
Go! Go! Move!
Get that shield door down!
No! Wait, don't shoot! It's us!
No! Don't shoot!
Hold your fire!
- Don't shoot!
- Hold your fire!
- Finn?
- Finn!
Rose! You're not dead!
Where's my droid?
Buddy!
I'm so glad to see you!
Wait, what?
Wait, wait, wait, slow down.
Is this all that's left?
All right, shields are up
so they can't hit us from orbit.
Use whatever power we've got left
to broadcast a distress signal
to the Outer Rim.
Use my personal code.
If there are any allies to the Resistance,
it's now or never.
Rose, what do you got?
Rotting munitions, rusted artillery,
some half-gutted skim speeders.
Well,
let's just pray that big-ass door
holds long enough for us
to get help.
A battering ram cannon.
A what now?
Miniaturized Death Star tech.
It'll crack that door open like an egg.
There has to be a back way
out of here, right?
BB-8, what do you got?
BB-8 has analyzed
the mine's schematics.
This is the only way in or out.
Come on.
We have allies.
People believe in Leia.
They'll get our message, they'll come.
But we have to buy time.
We gotta take out that cannon.
On me! On me!
Move! Move!
Go back! Gather your weapons!
Get over here!
Hold your fire!
Salt.
Ground forces, incoming.
Copy that. On our way.
Engage your mono-ski.
The green toggle.
All right, listen up.
I don't like these rust buckets
and I don't like our odds, but...
What the hell?
Just keep it tight
and don't get drawn in too close
till they roll that cannon out front.
All right, ground forces,
lay down some fire!
Thirteen incoming light craft.
Shall we hold until we clear them?
No. The Resistance
is in that mine.
Push through.
Fighters, break off!
Come on! We gotta hold them
till they pull up that cannon!
Rose, you got three right behind you!
I can't lose 'em!
Whoo! Yeah!
Whoo! I like this!
Blow that piece of junk out of the sky!
All fighters!
Chewie, peel off from the battle.
Draw them away from the speeders.
She drew 'em off! All of 'em!
Oh, they hate that ship!
Chewie!
There it is!
That is a big gun.
Okay, it's heavily armored.
Our only shot is right down the throat.
The cannon's opening.
This is our chance.
All firepower on those speeders.
Concentrate all fire on the speeders!
We're taking heavy losses.
They're picking us all off.
We're not gonna make it.
All right,
making my final approach.
Target in sight, guns are hot.
No! Pull off!
What?
The cannon is charged!
It's a suicide run!
All craft, pull away!
- No! I'm almost there!
- Retreat, Finn!
That's an order!
Finn? It's too late! Don't do this!
No! I won't let them win!
No! Finn, listen to Poe!
We have to retreat!
The cannon is warming up now.
Copy that. We see it.
Preparing to fire.
Move! Go, go! Quick!
Let's go, let's go!
Rose?
Why would you do that? Huh?
I was almost there.
Why would you stop me?
I saved you,
dummy.
That's how we're gonna win.
Not fighting what we hate,
saving what we love.
General Hux,
advance.
No quarter.
No prisoners.
Our distress signal's been
received at multiple points,
but no response.
They've heard us,
but no one's coming.
We fought till the end.
But the galaxy has lost all its hope.
The spark
is out.
Luke.
I know what you're gonna say.
I changed my hair.
It's nice that way.
Leia,
I'm sorry.
I know.
I know you are.
I'm just glad you're here
at the end.
I came to face him, Leia.
And I can't save him.
I held out hope for so long,
but I know my son is gone.
No one's ever really gone.
Master Luke.
Stop!
I want every gun we have
to fire on that man.
Do it.
More!
That's enough.
That's enough!
Do you think you got him?
Now, if we're ready to get moving,
we can finish this.
Sir?
Bring me down to him.
Keep the door covered
and don't advance until I say.
Supreme Leader,
don't get distracted, our goal...
Right away, sir.
Med pack!
I need a med pack!
She's hurt pretty bad.
It's Kylo Ren.
Luke's facing him alone.
Well, we should help him.
Let's go.
No, wait. Wait.
Did you come back to say you forgive me?
To save my soul?
No.
He's doing this for a reason.
He's stalling so we can escape.
Escape?
He's one man against an army.
We have to help him,
we have to fight.
No, no. We are the spark
that'll light the fire
that'll burn the First Order down.
Skywalker's doing this
so we can survive.
There's gotta be a way
out of this mine.
Hell, how did he get in here?
Sir, it is possible that
a natural unmapped opening exists.
But this facility is such
a maze of endless tunnels
that the odds of finding an exit
- are 15,428...
- Shh. Shush. Hush. Shush up.
Shut up!
- To one.
- Listen.
My audio sensors
no longer detect the...
Exactly.
Where'd the crystal critters go?
Follow me.
What are you looking at me for?
Follow him.
If the beacon's right beneath us,
they've got to be somewhere.
Keep scanning for life forms.
This way.
I see them! Chewie, there!
No. No, no, no.
No!
Lifting rocks.
I failed you, Ben.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm sure you are!
The Resistance is dead.
The war is over.
And when I kill you,
I will have killed the last Jedi.
Amazing.
Every word of what you just said
was wrong.
The Rebellion is reborn today.
The war
is just beginning.
And I will not be the last Jedi.
I'll destroy her,
and you,
and all of it.
No.
Strike me down in anger
and I'll always be with you.
Just like your father.
No.
See you around, kid.
No!
C'ai!
Such a friend.
Chewie!
It looks good.
That was crazy, man.
- Hi.
I'm Poe.
Rey.
I know.
When we get to the Outer Rim,
I have a contact there.
Quite definitely possible.
Luke is gone.
I felt it.
But it wasn't sadness or pain.
It was peace and purpose.
I felt it, too.
How do we build a Rebellion from this?
We have everything we need.
Luke Skywalker,
Jedi Master.
Psagmeno.com
Quality Movies Subs and Info